ageing: n.  老化
Lesson 37 The process of ageing
37  衰老过程
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
What is one of the most unpleasant discoveries we make about ourselves as we get older?
随着年龄增长,人类对自身最不愉快的发现是什么?
At the age of twelve years,the human body is at its most vigorous.
人体在12岁时是生命力最旺盛的时期.
It has yet to reach its full size and strength,
虽然在这个时期人的身材、体力还有待发展,
and its owner his or her full intelligence,
智力还有待发展和完善,
likelihood: n.  可能性
but at this age the likelihood of death is least.
但在这个年龄死亡的可能性最小.
infant: n.  婴儿
Earlier,we were infants and young children,
再早一些,我们是幼儿和小孩子,
and consequently more vulnerable;
身体较脆弱;
later,we shall undergo a progressive loss of our vigour and resistance
再迟一些,我们就要经历生命力和抵抗力逐步衰退的过程.
which,though imperceptible at first
虽然这个过程起初难以觉察,
will finally become so steep that we can live no longer,
但最终会急转直下,简直再也无法活下去了,
however well we look after ourselves,
不管我们怎样精心照料我们自己,
and however well society,and our doctors,look after us.
不管社会和医生怎样对我们进行精心照顾.
ageing: n.  老化
This decline in vigour with the passing of time is called ageing.
生命力随时间的流失而衰退叫做衰老.
It is one of the most unpleasant discoveries which we all make
人类发现的最不愉快的一个事实是:
that we must decline in this way,that if we escape wars,accidents and diseases,
人必然会衰老.即使我们能避开战争、意外的事故和各种疾病,
we shall eventually 'die of old age',
我们最终也会"老死",
and that this happens at a rate which differs little from person to person,
衰老的速度在人与人之间相差甚微,
odds: n.  可能性
so that there are heavy odds in favour of our dying between the ages of 65 and 80.
我们最可能死亡的年龄在65至80岁之间.
Some of us will die sooner,a few will live longer on into a ninth or tenth decade.
有些人会死得早一些,少数人寿命会长一些,活到八十几岁或九十几岁,
But the chances are against it,
但这种可能性很小,
and there is a virtual limit on how long we can hope to remain alive,
我们所希望的长寿实际上是有限度的,
however lucky and robust we are.
不管我们多么幸运,多么健壮.
Normal people tend to forget this process unless and until they are reminded of it.
衰老的过程,不经提起,正常人容易忘记:一经提醒才会记起.
We are so familiar with the fact that man ages,
我们对人总是要衰老的现象并不陌生,
that people have for years assumed that the process of losing vigour with time,
多年来就已认识到:生命力随着时间流失而丧失活力,
of becoming more likely to die the older we get,was something self-evident
人随着年龄的增长而接近死亡,这是不言而喻的,
like the cooling of a hot kettle or the wearing out of a pair of shoes.
就像一壶热水迟早会凉下来,一双鞋渐渐会磨破一样.
They have also assumed that all animals,
人们不但认识到所有的动物,
organism: n.  有机体
and probably other organisms such as trees,or even the universe itself,
大概也认识到所有的有机物,如树木,甚至宇宙本身,
must in the nature of things 'wear out'.
从事物的本质上来说都会"磨损掉".
Most animals we commonly observe do in fact age as we do,
我们通常看到的动物都会像我们一样衰老,
if given the chance to live long enough;
即使能让它们活得足够长久,也一样难逃衰老,
and mechanical systems like a wound watch,or the sun,
像上紧发条的手表那样的机械装置,或太阳,
thermodynamics: n.  热力学
do in fact run out of energy in accordance with the second law of thermodynamics
根据热力学第二定律,都会消耗完其能量,
(whether the whole universe does so is a moot point at present).
(整个宇宙是否如此,目前尚有争论).
But these are not analogous to what happens when man ages.
不过,这些衰老的情况同人并不相似.
A run down watch is still a watch and can be rewound.
手表停了依然是只手表,还可以重上好发条.
An old watch,by contrast,
然而一只老掉牙的手表,
becomes so worn and unreliable that it eventually is not worth mending.
磨损太厉害,老得一点儿也不准了,最终会不值得修理了.
But a watch could never repair itself,
但是,手表决不会自行修理,
it does not consist of living parts,only of metal,which wears away by friction.
它不是由有生命的部件组成,而是由金属组成,而金属可以因磨擦而磨损殆尽.
We could,at one time,repair ourselves well enough,at least,
而我们人,在一定时间内是可以自行修复的,至少,
to overcome all but the most instantly fatal illnesses and accidents.
除了暴病而死或意外事故外,足以克服一切一般疾病和事故.
Between twelve and eighty years we gradually lose this power;
在12岁至80岁之间,我们逐渐丧失这种能力,
an illness which at 12 would knock us over,at 80 can knock us out,and into our grave.
能使我们在12岁时病倒的疾病,到了80岁可能会使我们一蹶不振而进入坟墓.
If we could stay as vigorous as we are at twelve,
假如我们能保持12岁的旺盛生命力,
it would take about 700 years for half of us to die,
那么我们当中的一半人过700年才会死去,
and another 700 for the survivors to be reduced by half again.
剩下的一半人再过700年,才会又减少一半.